Welcome to Rust in Motion 1,
欢迎来到 Rust in Motion 第一章，
Getting Comfortable with Rust.
首先来熟悉 Rust。
Rust is an exciting new language aiming
Rust 是一门令人兴奋的新语言，旨在
to be an alternative to C
成为 C 和 C++ 的替代品
and C++,
，
with the same performance characteristics of those
具有与这些语言相同的性能特点
but with certain classes of common bugs
但在编译时消除了某些类别的
eliminated at compile time.
常见错误。
Rust is a general-purpose language.
Rust是一种通用语言。
But it's especially good in situations
但它在下面一些场景会特别好：
where runtime speed is needed,
在需要保证运行速度的场景，
memory safety is required,
在需要保证内存安全的场景，
and you want to take advantage of multiple processors.
还有在你需要充分利用多核处理器的场景。
Some areas in particular where Rust is
Rust 可以胜任的特别领域包括
poised to do well are high-performance
高性能web服务，
web services, WebAssembly,
WebAssembly，
command-line applications,
命令行程序，
and embedded devices.
和嵌入式设备。
Rust started as a Mozilla Research
Rust 诞生于 Mozilla Research
project,
项目。
and a significant example of production
Firefox 本身就是 Rust 能投入生产应用（而不是demo）
Rust usage is Firefox.
的一个重要例子。
Mozilla has been using Rust to create
Mozilla 使用 Rust 创建了
an experimental browser called Servo,
一个名为 Servo 的实验性质的浏览器，
where everything is parallelized.
在这款浏览器中，所有东西都是并行的。
Parts of Servo are now being incorporated
现在，Servo 的部分功能已经整合进
into Firefox.
Firefox 了。
The Firefox Quantum release included
Firefox Quantum 版包含了
Servo's CSS rendering engine.
Servo 项目的 CSS 渲染引擎。
Rust was a big part of the performance improvements
Rust 是 Firefox 在这方面性能提升的
Firefox made in that area.
一个重要因素。
Check out the Rust friends page to
查看 Rust friends 页面，
see a list of companies using Rust in
可以看到在生产环境中使用 Rust
production for everything from
的公司名单，
cryptocurrency to DevOps to big
从加密货币到 DevOps，再到
data.
大数据。
Speed, safety,
速度，安全，
and fearless concurrency
还有无畏并发
are the benefits of Rust.
都是 Rust 的优点。
One of the downsides of Rust is that it has
Rust 的缺点之一是
a reputation of being hard to learn,
它以难学著称，
and that's why we're here.
这就是我们这门课的意义所在。
I'm Carol Nichols.
我是 Carol Nichols。
I'm a Ruby developer who got into Rust
我是一名 Ruby 开发人员，
to write better-performing code that wasn't
为了编写性能更好的代码，我选择转向 Rust，而不是转向
C.
C 语言。
I'm on the Rust Core team,
我现在在 Rust Core 团队中，
I'm the co-author of ﻿The Rust Programming Language book,﻿
我是 The Rust Programming Language 一书的合著者，
and I maintain crates.io – the Rust Package
同时我还维护着 crates.io – Rust 官方提供的
Registry.
包的发布地。
Rust is especially exciting to me because
Rust 让我非常兴奋，因为
I think this is an opportunity for the software
我认为这是软件行业的一个机会，
industry to start making some new mistakes,
能够只犯普通错误
instead of the same memory safety problems
而不是不断的内存安全错误。
that lead to security vulnerabilities
而这些内存安全问题
that continue to happen over
会导致安全漏洞
and over.
不断发生。
And I'm Jake Goulding.
我是 Jake Goulding。
I'm a full stack developer, from C
我是一名全栈开发人员，从 C
to Ruby to JavaScript.
到 Ruby 再到 JavaScript。
I'm a member of the Rust Infrastructure team,
我是 Rust 基础设施团队的一员，
I'm the number one answerer for Rust questions
我是 Stack Overflow 上 Rust 相关问题的
on Stack Overflow,
头号回答者。
and I maintain the Rust playground at
我还负责维护 play.rust-lang.org 上的
play.rust-lang.org.
在线 Rust 运行网站。
Some of my previous work involved heavy
我以前的一些工作涉及到
XML processing using libxml2.
使用 libxml2 进行繁重的 XML 处理。
I started programming in Rust because I
现在我开始使用 Rust 编程是因为
believe it is capable of improving
我相信它能够提高
the safety and correctness of things
安全性和正确性，
like XML processing without
比如 XML 处理，
losing any of the performance we expect
同时又不会损失任何我们期望的
from a systems programming language.
系统级编程语言的性能。
We founded Integer 32,
我们创立了 Integer 32，
the world's first Rust-focused software
这是世界上首家专注于 Rust 的
consultancy,
软件咨询公司，
and we love helping people learn Rust.
我们喜欢帮助人们学习 Rust。
I'll be teaching units 1
我会教第一章
and 3. And you'll hear from me
和第三章。而我会教
for units 2
第二章
and 4.
和第四章。
Rust has quite a few concepts that
Rust 有很多
are different than most other mainstream languages
与当今大多数其他主流语言不同的概念
today.
。
If you try to jump into the deep end
如果你在不熟悉这些概念的情况下
with Rust without becoming familiar
尝试深入了解 Rust，
with these concepts, it can be a
这可能会令人
frustrating experience.
沮丧。
We're going to go through these concepts so that you're ready
我们将介绍这些概念，以便
to think in Rust as you continue on
你能够在继续 Rust 之旅时
your Rust journey.
进行思考。
In unit 1,
在第一单元，
we're going to introduce basic syntax
我们将介绍一些结构的基本语法，
for constructs that you've likely encountered
这些结构你可能在其他语言中遇到过，
in other languages like variables,
比如变量、
data types, and functions.
数据类型和函数。
But we'll be concentrating on what makes them different
但我们将专注于那些在 Rust 中不同的部分
in Rust.
。
In unit 2, we'll cover the concepts of ownership
在第二章，我们将介绍所有权
and borrowing. These concepts
和借用所有权的概念。这些概念
permeate all Rust code
渗透到所有 Rust 的代码中，
and they help ensure memory safety
他们有助于确保 Rust 中的内存安全
in Rust.
。
In unit 3,
在第三章，
we'll talk about Rust's strategy for
我们将讨论 Rust 的
error handling.
错误处理机制。
Rust forces you to consider all the ways
Rust 迫使你考虑程序可能失败的
your program might fail, which can
所有场景，这在
be frustrating while prototyping,
原型设计时可能会令人沮丧，
but leads to more robust production code.
但这会生成更健壮的产品代码。
In unit 4, we'll concentrate on lifetimes –
在第四章，我们将专注于生命周期概念 –
the mechanism that the compiler uses to
一个编译器用来确保所有引用
ensure all references are valid.
都有效的机制。
You can write a lot of Rust code without needing
一般来说你可以编写大量 Rust 代码而无需担心
to worry about explicit lifetime annotations.
显式的生命周期注释。
But we don't want them to be intimidating if you encounter
但我们不希望
them in error messages
当你在错误消息
or when reading other people's code.
或是在阅读其他人代码遇到他们时感到畏惧。
We'll demystify the concept
我们将揭开这个概念的神秘面纱，
and go through scenarios when lifetime
并研究需要生命周期注释的
annotations are needed.
场景。
A theme in all of these units
贯穿这些章节的一点是
is that the Rust compiler is here to
Rust 编译器可以帮助你
help you write better code.
编写更好的代码。（译者注，此句翻译拿捏不住）
That means it's very common to get compiler
这意味着在你工作时
errors when you're working.
出现编译器报错是很常见的。
Even experienced Rust programmers get compiler
即使是有经验的 Rust 程序员
errors all the time.
也会经常遇到编译器报错。
People have put a lot of work into making
Rust 开发者们已经投入了大量工作来使
the messages understandable
这些报错信息易于理解
and helpful,
并在报错里提供了帮助信息，
so we'll be intentionally causing errors throughout
因此我们将在整个课程中故意制造一些错误，
the course to get experience reading
以便获得阅读和
and responding to errors.
处理错误的经验
Let's  install Rust
让我们安装 Rust
and get started!
然后开始吧！